[birds chirping]
[Coco yawns loudly]
[Agott gasps]
[sighs]
[Agott clears throat]
[Coco chuckles]
[COCO] Uh...
Was I making too much noise?
[wind howling]
[Agott sighs]
[AGOTT] The light is weak.
And it lacks stability.
- [bird screeching]
- [gasps]
[exclaims softly]
[gasps]
[bird screeching]
[wind howling]
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[Coco sighs]
Still wobbly.
I was supposed to choose
a pen in Kalhn.
But I never got the chance.
A LIGHT ON A RAINY DAY
When I'm using
a Pigment Stone,
I can draw nice, straight lines.
But that's hardly ideal
for small paper like this.
[Coco exhales]
[inhales]
[exhales]
[wind howling]
I'm the only one
who didn't cast a single spell
of their own that day.
Master told me ideas were
important to magic, but still.
Stop that! No moping around!
Practice! Over and over again!
Till you finally
get used to it!
That's the way! [grunts]
[Coco yawns]
[sighs]
So tired.
[Coco sighs]
[QIFREY] I wouldn't
sleep out here.
You're likely to catch a cold.
[Coco gasps]
[COCO] It wasn't
my intention to, but...
I suddenly felt tired.
[QIFREY] Hm.
If I keep going like this,
I'll never pass
the Tower of Tomes test,
or find the book,
will I?
No! I have to stop
beating myself up!
- [QIFREY] Uh?
- I'm wrong! I can do it!
I love magic too much to fail!
[QIFREY] Coco.
[COCO] Hm?
Would you come along with me
for a moment?
[footsteps]
[COCO] The kitchen?
Smells so nice.
[QIFREY] I need
to free up this pot.
Perhaps you'd be
willing to help?
Here. Have a taste.
[Coco blows]
[exclaims softly]
So good!
[Coco exclaims]
[QIFREY] Isn't it?
Especially for being
two years old.
[Coco gasps]
The Magic Cookpot
keeps repeating
the moment the stew was made,
so it doesn't go bad.
And thus...
good as new.
- That said...
- [Coco gasps]
The spell needs
to be redrawn regularly,
otherwise it will
eventually wear out.
[COCO] Huh?
Carapace yams!
Yes.
These are so delicious.
They are indeed. Would you
like to try cooking one
- for me?
- Huh?
I believe you've learned
to draw the Pyreball spell,
haven't you?
[Coco gasps, grunts]
♪
[Coco sighs softly]
[pen scratching]
Huh? But why?
The yams are heavy,
so the Sign of Levitation
- needs longer rays.
- Oh.
[QIFREY] You don't want
the flame too small
- or unbalanced.
- [Coco gasps]
[QIFREY] In this case,
your sigil was too large.
Go on. Give it another try.
[pen scratching]
[Coco chuckles softly]
[fire crackling]
One nice, toasty yam!
[Qifrey chuckles]
[QIFREY] And cooked perfectly,
at that!
[Coco gasps softly]
- [QIFREY] Now, then...
- Huh?
Are you still tired?
[COCO] Uh?
As for me,
when I was learning magic,
the first kind I mastered...
was that of water.
I was never much of a swimmer,
but in truth, I didn't like
getting wet for any reason.
So I practiced
water magic constantly
to avoid washing things by hand.
[Coco gasps softly]
If you're trying
to learn something new
and you're desperate
to make it happen quickly...
then build it into
your daily routine.
For after all,
life itself truly
is the best teacher
this world has to offer.
My daily...
routine?
Start with cooking,
good food and good practice!
- Good point!
- [TETIA] Oh?
I thought I smelled
something yummy,
and it looks like
I was absolutely right!
Allow me!
I'd like to volunteer
as cheese melter!
Adding grill marks with magic
would be a nice touch.
[QIFREY] My thanks
to both of you,
but for today,
Coco's the one in charge.
Is that all right?
Yes!
♪
[Coco exclaims]
[COCO] Finished!
- [TETIA] Looks so good!
- [RICHEH] Perfection.
I know!
Let's take our food outside
and eat it there!
Wonderful idea!
Like a picnic!
[both giggle]
I shall make
all the necessary preparations.
[COCO] Oh, Agott!
We're having lunch outside!
Would you like to come with us?
Kind of you to ask,
but I do believe I'll pass.
I'm going to eat while I work.
And besides...
[COCO] It's raining?
Aw! But the weather was
so lovely a few minutes ago!
- [footsteps]
- What a shame.
And Master was just telling me
how much he hates getting wet.
- [QIFREY] What's this?
- [ALL] Huh?
Now, why do you all look
so disappointed?
[footsteps]
[all gasping]
Did you forget?
We are witches, are we not?
Come now, gather your things,
and let us be off.
♪
- [brushbuddy squeaks]
- [Coco gasps]
[QIFREY] Look.
There go the rain clouds.
♪
[Coco exclaims excitedly]
[QIFREY] Coco.
[COCO] I have to go get Agott
and bring her here!
She's going to miss it!
The magic the sky
shared with us!
[Coco panting]
Ago... Uh?
[MAN] Who are you?
Haven't seen you before.
Are you a messenger,
from Alaira?
- No, actually... I, uh...
- [QIFREY] Coco!
There's another storm
approaching, so...
[MAN] Hm?
[QIFREY] Uh? [sighs]
[COCO] I'm an apprentice
to Master Qifrey!
I'm just new!
[man grunts]
You're what?
An apprentice?
Qifrey!
Greetings, Olruggio!
Finished your work, have you?
I thought it was
going to take you--
You took on another apprentice
in my absence?
[QIFREY] It's more complicated
than that.
You see, forbidden magic
was involved.
[OLRUGGIO] Forbidden magic?
Come.
Olruggio!
[Coco whimpers softly]
We'll have nothing to do
with the Brimmed Caps here.
I'm turning this girl in
to the Knights Moralis.
[Coco whimpers]
[COCO] Wait, please! I...
[Olruggio gasps]
[QIFREY] I'm sorry,
my dear friend,
but I'll stop anyone
who tries to take Coco.
Even you.
You'd turn your magic
against me for her sake?
Who is this girl?
[QIFREY]
First, let us go inside.
We have much to discuss.
[windows rattling]
[TETIA] That break in the clouds
felt like it was over.
But now it's coming down
even harder than before.
- [windows rattling]
- [TETIA] Uh?
Oh, dear.
Looks like we're in for a storm!
I agree.
We certainly are.
You actually brought on
an Outsider as an apprentice.
"Outsider" is an offensive term.
Her name is Coco.
[OLRUGGIO] I'm sorry, Coco.
That just happens to be
the only word we have
for people who aren't witches.
- [Olruggio slurping]
- This is the first time
you've met, yes?
[QIFREY]
May I present Olruggio.
The Watchful Eye
at this atelier.
[QIFREY] Unlike Kalhn
and the Great Hall,
small, rural ateliers like ours
have a tendency to be
rather isolated.
For this reason, a witch
is assigned as a "Watchful Eye"
to oversee matters
and ensure we don't cover up
any problems that arise.
Problems such as the one
you've been covering up here,
right under my very nose.
That night,
if I'd erased her memories,
our only lead to
the forbidden magic picture book
would have been lost,
along with her mother's chances
of being restored.
This seemed to be the best path
for all concerned.
[OLRUGGIO] "Lead," you say?
Investigating forbidden magic
is not within our purview.
We need to leave
all this to the Knights Moralis.
[Olruggio sighs]
[QIFREY] "Who are these
Knights Moralis
they keep talking about?"
- [Coco gasps]
- You're wondering, aren't you?
Also called the Order
of Moral Spellcasting,
the Knights Moralis
are the guardians
of magic itself.
In accordance
with the codes enacted
on the Day of the Pact,
they erase the memories of those
who dabble in forbidden magic
or discover magic's secrets.
They act strictly in accordance
with the rules,
granting no exception.
If I were to hand you over
to them,
they would then erase even
your passion for magic itself.
[Coco gasps]
You're a good girl, Coco.
You work hard,
you care for your mother,
and your love
of our craft is pure.
The fault is mine that
you learned our secret.
If Coco's memories
should indeed be erased,
it's only right that
the same be done to my own.
[Olruggio gasps]
[Olruggio grunts]
[OLRUGGIO] Damn it!
When you asked to take on
the other three apprentices,
I foolishly took it to mean
you'd finally settled down.
[both grunt softly]
[OLRUGGIO] Do what you want.
Know this...
should anything go awry,
I shall report it
to the Great Hall at once.
I don't intend to shirk my duty
as Watchful Eye.
- [COCO] Master Qifrey?
- [QIFREY] Be at ease.
You passed the test
with your own magic power.
Thus, you're
my official apprentice.
You deserve to be here.
[Coco gasps softly]
Thank you!
[BOTH] Hm.
Now, all of you,
run along and wash up now
before you catch your death!
[ALL] All right.
[pen scratching]
[COCO] Brushbuddy?
Where are you, brushbuddy?
Come on. Where'd you go?
[brushbuddy squeaks]
[COCO] Brushbuddy, no!
Not that way!
[brushbuddy squeaks]
[Coco gasps]
[COCO] No! Anywhere but there!
[Coco sighs]
[COCO] Hm.
[gasps]
[COCO] "A curse upon
any who knock at this door"?
[Coco gasps, whimpers]
♪
[door creaks]
[COCO] Um...
Pardon me.
Brushbuddy?
Come along now!
Let's go get nice
and dry together!
[Coco sneezes]
[OLRUGGIO] Oi.
- [clattering]
- [footsteps]
[OLRUGGIO] Didn't you read
the warning on the door?
[brushbuddy squeaks]
The point of it
is to keep people out.
[Coco gasps]
[OLRUGGIO] Hm?
Something in your lughole?
[Coco gasps]
No, sorry. Hold on.
You were soaked before,
but now you're dry.
- [Coco gasps softly]
- [brushbuddy squeaks softly]
[COCO] It's so warm.
I can feel my hair drying!
This is...
Mr. Olruggio's magic?
[Coco gasps]
[COCO] Huh?
Thank you very much.
I can't have you
catching a cold, can I?
I am the Watchful Eye.
[COCO]
And you watch our health?
[OLRUGGIO] It's my own fault
for leaving my door open.
You may now take your leave.
And don't...
- [Coco exclaims]
- Hm?
I was saying,
don't touch anything!
Mm?
[COCO] Oh, this spell...
[Coco exclaims]
It's the one that first made me
fall in love with magic!
It makes the ground shiny!
The Glowstone Path.
That one's my best work.
[Coco exclaims excitedly]
[OLRUGGIO] One stone
is layered over another,
and when weight is applied,
the sigil and ring overlap.
A simple spell
that anyone could...
- [gasps] What are you doing?
- [Coco exclaims]
Look, they're glowing!
[OLRUGGIO] Aye.
As the name rather suggests.
- [OLRUGGIO] Mm?
- I love this light.
It's very special to me.
[COCO] When I walked
on the stones, they lit up,
and suddenly, it was like
the magic was a part of me.
It was beautiful.
I cherished every step I took.
Parts of the memory are sad.
But mostly...
I remember this spell
allowed me to dream.
- And so...
- [OLRUGGIO] Hm?
Thank you from my heart,
Master Olruggio!
[Olruggio gasps]
[Olruggio stuttering]
I am not your master!
Now be on your way!
[COCO] Hm.
[door creaks]
[Olruggio grunts softly]
So they'd even take away
her passion.
Well...
[COCO] Wow, it's still raining.
[AGOTT] Mm-hm.
All right, then,
I'm going to study
in the living room today.
Say, why don't you join me?
[AGOTT] I won't, thank you.
I find it easier
to concentrate here.
Makes sense.
Well, in that case,
I'll call for you at lunchtime!
[door opens]
[door closes]
[window rattling]
[wind howling]
- [thudding]
- [Agott grunts]
[window rattling]
[pen scratching]
[window continues rattling]
[AGOTT] Come on.
The noise is endless!
I can't focus!
[Agott grunts]
[AGOTT] Very well...
Enduring these unpleasant sounds
shall be part of my training.
[Agott breathes deeply]
[pen scratching]
[AGOTT]
There's still some wavering,
but it's gotten more stable.
Soon, I can take the next test,
and work in the outside world.
I'm getting close!
Right. Once more.
[horse neighs]
[banging on door]
[MAN] Help me! Please!
There's a witch
living here, right?
[TETIA] Master!
What is it now?
[QIFREY]
I understand the situation,
but would you be able
to tell me...
[MAN] Please, Sir Witch,
there's no time!
Help us!
[QIFREY] All right, all right,
I'll help you.
I simply need to get ready.
- [MAN] Please hurry...
- [AGOTT] What's going on?
Because of all the rain,
the bridge across
the Staircase River collapsed.
There was a carriage on it,
now it's trapped
in the middle of the river.
It's too dangerous
for anyone to get close.
[Agott grunts softly]
- [MAN] My son...
- [all gasp]
My son was inside that carriage!
Yes, I know. Please, stay calm.
I'll do my best to hurry.
- [MAN] Thank you!
- [AGOTT] Outside work.
[QIFREY] My colleague and I
will do all we can.
[AGOTT] Master...
Agott, all of you stay here
where it's safe.
[AGOTT] No.
Please, allow me to come along!
I will be of use to you.
I promise!
[♪ closing theme song playing]
EPISODE 7:
WHO IS MAGIC FOR?